

# Aleksander Chako

E-mail: a.chako2012@gmail.com Website: <a href="https://achako2012.github.io/cv/">https://achako2012.github.io/cv/</a>

Phone: +380982829279

# Objective

Quality assurance engineer with more than 2 years of professional experience in testing web applications using modern technologies. Experience in manual and automation testing. A dedicated team player with great analytical skills, strong attention to detail, and well-developed time management abilities.

### Core skills:

- · A clear understanding of software development life cycle
- Knowledge of test types and levels, test design techniques
- A clear understanding of client-server architecture; micro-servers architecture; REST architecture and SOAP protocol; Knowledge of HTTP protocol
- A clear understanding of the Selenium WebDriver framework and Selenium W3C protocol
- Experience in UI Automation testing with JS
- Experience with BDD development
- · Basic knowledge of React
- · Basic knowledge of SQL

# **Trainings**

- Start IT QA Start
- Start IT API Testing Start
- QA Light Web Servers testing
- · QA Light Web servers and Web services
- Hillel Java for QA Automation
- Udemy JS and React courses
- Udemy Automated Software Testing with WebDriverIO

### Education

Faculty Transport Technology, speciality

2009 - 2014

#### Organization of International Transport

Pryazovkiy State Technical University

# Work experience

#### KindGeek

November 2020 — Present

#### AQA Engineer

- Performed Regression testing to make sure that the operations staff can see the communication in cleartext.
- Expertise in Smoke testing, Regression testing, System Testing and UAT.
- Creates and maintains integrations with our suite of tools to support CI
- Creation and maintenance of tools to improve test processes
- Creation and maintenance of UI/Functional tests for web with Protractor framework
- Creation and maintenance of automation test strategy
- · Testing and reporting issues in bug tracking database
- Creation and maintenance of API tests

#### **Terrasoft**

March 2020 — November 2020

#### QA engineer

- Worked with Product, Design, and Engineering teams on requirements gathering and evaluation
- Performed Regression testing to make sure that the operations staff can see the communication in cleartext.
- Extensive Knowledge in Agile Methodology and participated in Sprint planning, Sprint Retrospective, Product Backlog Refinement and daily Scrum meetings
- Experience in automating regression test cases using Selenium WebDriver.
- Tested API with Mocha testing framework and Axios.
- Developed Test Scripts to implement Test Cases, Test Scenarios, and features for BDD (Behaviour Driven Development), TDD (Test Driven Development) using Cucumber in Gherkins format.
- Good hands-on experience on bug tracking tool like Jira
- Expertise in Smoke testing, Regression testing, System Testing and UAT.
- Experience in Manual Testing of CRM systems
- Experience in Demo new features for acceptance.

#### **Smart Trader Labs**

April 2019 — Februar 2020

#### QA engineer

- Performed Functional, Smoke, Integration, System and Regression Testing of the web-based application
- Followed Agile Scrum methodology in Software Development
- Participating in daily stand up meetings, status meeting and retrospective meetings
- Worked closely with developers and business analysts to ensure that the application met the user expectations.
- Performing Defect tracking, defect reporting and defect reproducing using automated defect tracking tool, JIRA.
- Executing test cases for validating GUI and system functionality
- Performed web services testing via Restful web services.

Aleksander Chako 2

### Freelance (Web application)

February 2019 — April 2019

#### QA engineer

- Effectively used daily stand-ups for providing the status and raise impediments if dependencies got delayed.
- Prepared Test Plan, Test Cases, and Test Summary Reports
- Executing test cases for validating GUI and system functionality
- Performing Defect tracking, defect reporting, and defect reproducing using automated defect tracking tool, JIRA.

### Languages:

- Russian, Ukrainian native
- English upper-intermediate

Aleksander Chako